{"name": "\u65e7OG2  2MC", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. A restaurant occupying the top floor of a skyscraper rotates as diners enjoy the view. Ling and Sarah notice that they began their meal at 7:00 P.M. looking due north. At 7:45 P.M. they had rotated 180\u00b0 to a view that was due south. At this rate, how many degrees will the restaurant rotate in 1 hour ?", "choices": {"A": "90\u00b0", "B": "180\u00b0", "C": "240\u00b0", "D": "270\u00b0", "E": "400\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. If 12 vases cost \uff0418.00, what is the cost of 1 vase ?", "choices": {"A": "$0.67", "B": "$1.05", "C": "$1.33", "D": "$1.50", "E": "$1.60"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Your friend shows you a scale drawing of her apartment. The drawing of the apartment is a rectangle 4 inches by 6 inches. Your friend wants to know the length of the shorter side of the apartment. If she knows that the length of the longer side of the apartment is 30 feet, how many feet long is the shorter side of her apartment ?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "20", "C": "24", "D": "30", "E": "45"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. A company earned a profit of $8.0 million each year for 3 consecutive years. For each of the next 2 years the company earned a profit of $9.0 million. For this 5-year period, what was the company\u2019s average yearly profit, in millions of dollars ?", "choices": {"A": "8.2", "B": "8.25", "C": "8.4", "D": "8.5", "E": "8.6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. A company rents moving vans for a rental fee of $25.00 per day with an additional charge of $0.30 per mile that the van is driven. Which of the following expressions represents the cost, in dollars, of renting a van for 1 day and driving it m miles ?", "choices": {"A": "0.30m + 25", "B": "25m + 30", "C": "30m + 25", "D": "25.30m", "E": "55m"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The figure below shows quadrilateral ABCD. What is the measure of \u2220C ?", "choices": {"A": "120\u00b0", "B": "115\u00b0", "C": "105\u00b0", "D": "100\u00b0", "E": "80\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. In the figure below, \u25b3ABC and \u25b3DEF are similar triangles with the given side lengths in meters. What is the perimeter, in meters, of \u25b3DEF ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "8", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "13"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The relationship between temperature in degrees Fahrenheit, F, and temperature in degrees Celsius, C, is expressed by the formula. Calvin reads a temperature of 38\u00b0 on a Celsius thermometer. To the nearest degree, what is the equivalent temperature on a Fahrenheit thermometer ?", "choices": {"A": "36\u00b0", "B": "53\u00b0", "C": "68\u00b0", "D": " 70\u00b0", "E": " 100\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  Nick needs to order 500 pens from his supplier. The catalog shows that these pens come in cases of 24 boxes with 10 pens in each box. Nick knows that he may NOT order partial cases. What is the fewest number of cases he should order ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": " 3", "C": " 18", "D": " 21", "E": " 50"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. When a + b = 6, what is the value of ", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": "37", "C": "38", "D": "43", "E": "47"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. The cost of a hamburger and a soft drink together is $2.10. The cost of 2 hamburgers and a soft drink together is $3.50. What is the cost of a soft drink ?", "choices": {"A": "$0.50", "B": "$0.55", "C": "$0.70", "D": "$1.05", "E": "$1.40"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  If 12x = -8(10 - x), then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "8", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "-20"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Shannon is planning to tile a rectangular kitchen countertop that is 24 inches wide and 64 inches long. She determined that 1 tile will be needed for each 4-inch-by-4-inch region. What is the minimum number of tiles that will be needed to completely cover the countertop to its edges ?", "choices": {"A": "44", "B": "88", "C": "96", "D": "176", "E": "384"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Which of the following lists gives 2 of the 3 interior angle measurements of a triangle for which the 3rd angle measurement would be equal to 1 of the 2 given measurements ?", "choices": {"A": "20\u00b0, 40\u00b0", "B": "30\u00b0, 60\u00b0", "C": "40\u00b0, 100\u00b0", "D": "45\u00b0, 120\u00b0", "E": "50\u00b0, 60\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. A triangle with a perimeter of 66 inches has one side that is 16 inches long. The lengths of the other two sides have a ratio of 2:3. What is the length, in inches, of the longest side of the triangle ?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "20", "C": "30", "D": "40", "E": "50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the y-intercept of the line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane that goes through the points (-3, 6) and (3, 2) ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. In the figure below, lines m and n are parallel, transversals r and s intersect to form an angle of measure x\u00b0, and 2 other angle measures are as marked. What is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "25", "C": "35", "D": "65", "E": "80"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The depth of a pond is 180 cm and is being reduced by 1 cm per week. The depth of a second pond is 160 cm and is being reduced by  cm per week. If the depths of both ponds continue to be reduced at these constant rates, in about how many weeks will the ponds have the same depth ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "20", "C": "40", "D": "80", "E": "140"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. When graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, which of the following equations does NOT represent a line ?", "choices": {"A": "x = 4", "B": "3y = 6", "C": " x - y = 1", "D": "", "E": "x2 + y = 5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In the right triangle shown below, which of the following statements is true about \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the slope of any line parallel to the line 7x + 9y = 6 ?", "choices": {"A": "-7", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The braking distance, y feet, for Damon\u2019s car to come to a complete stop is modeled by , where x is the speed of the car in miles per hour. According to this model, which of the following is the maximum speed, in miles per hour, Damon can be driving so that the braking distance is less than or equal to 150 feet ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "30", "C": "40", "D": "50", "E": "60"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. If  and , then what is the value of  ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "4"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. At a school picnic, 1 junior and 1 senior will be selected to lead the activities. If there are 125 juniors and 100 seniors at the picnic, how many different 2-person combinations of 1 junior and 1 senior are possible ?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "100", "C": "125", "D": "225", "E": "12,500"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. A ramp for wheelchair access to the gym has a slope of 5% (that is, the ramp rises 5 feet vertically for every 100 feet of horizontal distance). The entire ramp is built on level ground, and the entrance to the gym is 2 feet above the ground. What is the horizontal distance, in feet, between the ends of the ramp ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "10", "C": "40", "D": "100", "E": "400"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The temperature, t, in degrees Fahrenheit, in a certain town on a certain spring day satisfies the inequality . Which of the following temperatures, in degrees Fahrenheit, is NOT in this range ?", "choices": {"A": "-10", "B": "-6", "C": "-5", "D": "0", "E": "54"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. If 5 times a number n is subtracted from 15, the result is negative. Which of the following gives the possible value(s) for n ?", "choices": {"A": "0 only", "B": "3 only", "C": "10 only", "D": "All n \uff1e3", "E": "All n \uff1c3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. (x2 - 4x + 3) - (3x2 - 4x - 3) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "2x2 - 6", "B": "2x2 - 8x ", "C": "2x2 - 8x - 6", "D": "-2x2 + 6", "E": "-2x2 - 8x"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. The median of a set of data containing 9 items was found. Four data items were added to the set. Two of these items were greater than the original median, and the other 2 items were less than the original median. Which of the following statements must be true about the median of the new data set ?", "choices": {"A": "It is the average of the 2 new lower values.", "B": "It is the same as the original median.", "C": "It is the average of the 2 new higher values.", "D": "It is greater than the original median.", "E": "It is less than the original median."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. The figure below shows 2 tangent circles such that the 10-centimeter diameter of the smaller circle is equal to the radius of the larger circle. What is the area, in square centimeters, of the shaded region ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "75", "C": "5\u03c0", "D": "10\u03c0", "E": "75\u03c0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Which of the following sets of 3 numbers could be the side lengths, in meters, of a 30\u00b0 -60\u00b0-90\u00b0 triangle ?", "choices": {"A": "1, 1, 1", "B": "1, 1, ", "C": "1, ,", "D": "1, ,", "E": "1, , 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The curve y = 0.005x2 - 2x + 200 for 0 \u2264 x \u2264 200 and the line segment from F(0,200) to G(200,0) are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.32. What is the y-coordinate for the point on the curve with x-coordinate 20 ?", "choices": {"A": "160", "B": "162", "C": "164", "D": "166", "E": "168"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The curve y = 0.005x2 - 2x + 200 for 0 \u2264 x \u2264 200 and the line segment from F(0,200) to G(200,0) are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.33. The length of this curve is longer than FG. About how many coordinate units long is FG ?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "141", "C": "200", "D": "283", "E": "400"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The curve y = 0.005x2 - 2x + 200 for 0 \u2264 x \u2264 200 and the line segment from F(0,200) to G(200,0) are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.34. Tran wants to approximate the area underneath the curve y = 0.005x2 - 2x + 200 for 0 \u2264 x \u2264 200, shown shaded in the graph below.He finds an initial estimate, A, for the shaded area by using FG and computing A = (200 units)(200 units)= 20,000 square units. The area of the shaded region is:", "choices": {"A": " less than 20,000 square units, because the curve lies under FG.", "B": " less than 20,000 square units, because the curve lies over FG.", "C": " equal to 20,000 square units.", "D": " greater than 20,000 square units, because the curve lies under FG.", "E": " greater than 20,000 square units, because the curve lies over FG."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A cargo ship is 4.2 miles from a lighthouse, and a fishing boat is 5.0 miles from the lighthouse, as shown below. The angle between the straight lines from the lighthouse to the 2 vessels is 5\u00b0. The approximate distance, in miles, from the cargo ship to the fishing boat is given by which of the following expressions ? (Note: The law of cosines states that for any triangle with vertices A, B, and C and the sides opposite those vertices with lengths a, b, and c, respectively, c2 = a2 + b2 - 2ab cos C.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following equations expresses c in terms of a for all real numbers a, b, and c such that a3 = b and b2 = c ?", "choices": {"A": "c = a6", "B": "c = a5", "C": "c = 2a3", "D": "", "E": "c = a"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Which of the following statements is NOT true about the arithmetic sequence 17, 12, 7, 2, \u2022\u2022\u2022 ?", "choices": {"A": "The fifth term is -3.", "B": "The sum of the first 5 terms is 35.", "C": "The eighth term is -18.", "D": "The common difference of consecutive terms is -5.", "E": "The common ratio of consecutive terms is -5."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, the points (0.0), (10,0), (13,6), and (3,6) are the vertices of a parallelogram. What is the area, in square coordinate units, of the parallelogram ?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "60", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The normal amount of lead in a certain water supply is 1.5 \u00d7 10-5 milligrams per liter. Today, when the water was tested, the lead level found was exactly 100 times as great as the normal level, still well below the Environmental Protection Agency\u2019s action level. What concentration of lead, in milligrams per liter, was in the water tested today ?", "choices": {"A": "1.5 \u00d7 10-105", "B": "1.5 \u00d7 10-10", "C": "1.5 \u00d7 10-7", "D": "1.5 \u00d7 10-3", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. A certain perfect square has exactly 4 digits (that is, it is an integer between 1,000 and 9,999). The positive square root of the perfect square must have how many digits ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "x2 + y2", "E": "x2 - xy + y2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. What is the matrix product [1   0   -1] ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "[2a   0   -2a]", "D": "[6a   0   -6a]", "E": "[0]"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. What is the degree measure of the smaller of the 2 angles formed by the line and the ray shown in the figure below ?", "choices": {"A": "14\u00b0", "B": "28\u00b0", "C": "29\u00b0", "D": "58\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. How many prime numbers are there between 30 and 50 ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The lengths, in feet, of the sides of right triangle \u25b3ABC are as shown in the diagram below, with x &gt; 0. What is the cotangent of \u2220A, in terms of x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. A restaurant has 10 booths that will seat up to 4 people each. If 20 people are seated in booths, and NO booths are empty, what is the greatest possible number of booths that could be filled with 4 people ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The trapezoid below is divided into 2 triangles and 1 rectangle. Lengths are given in inches. What is the combined area, in square inches, of the 2 shaded triangles ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "9", "D": "12", "E": "18"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the figure below, ABCD is a square and E, F, G, and H are the midpoints of its sides. If AB = 12 inches, what is the perimeter of EFGH, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Which of the following expressions, if any, are equal for all real numbers x ?I. II.  III.  ", "choices": {"A": "I and II only", "B": "I and III only", "C": " II and III only", "D": "I, II, and III", "E": "None of the expressions are equivalent."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In the figure below, A, C, F, and D are collinear; B, C, and E are collinear; and the angles at A, E, and F are right angles, as marked. Which of the following statements is NOT justifiable from the given information ? ", "choices": {"A": " is parallel to.", "B": "DE is perpendicular to BE.", "C": "\u2220ACB is congruent to \u2220FCE.", "D": "\u25b3BAC is similar to \u25b3EFC.", "E": "CE is congruent to ED."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the figure below, all line segments are either horizontal or vertical and the dimensions given are in inches. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the figure ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "12", "C": "13", "D": "14", "E": "16"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. A 6-inch-by-8-inch rectangle is inscribed in a circle as shown below. What is the area of the circle, in square inches ?", "choices": {"A": "5\u03c0", "B": "16\u03c0", "C": "25\u03c0", "D": "48\u03c0", "E": "96\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. On his first day as a telemarketer, Marshall made 24 calls. His goal was to make 5 more calls on each successive day than he had made the day before. If Marshall met, but did not exceed, his goal, how many calls had he made in all after spending exactly 20 days making calls as a telemarketer ?", "choices": {"A": "670", "B": "690", "C": "974", "D": "1,430", "E": "1,530"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Which of the following is the graph of the function f(x) defined below ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. If the value, to the nearest thousandth, of cos \u03b8 is -0.385, which of the following could be true about \u03b8 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Which of the following quadratic equations has solutions x = 6a  and x = -3b ?", "choices": {"A": "x2 - 18ab = 0", "B": "x2 - x(3b - 6a) - 18ab = 0", "C": "x2 - x(3b + 6a) + 18ab = 0", "D": "x2 + x(3b - 6a) - 18ab = 0", "E": "x2 + x(3b + 6a) + 18ab = 0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. In the standard\uff08x, y\uff09coordinate plane below, the vertices of the square have coordinates (0,0), (6,0), (6,6) and (0,6). Which of the following is an equation of the circle that is inscribed in the square ?", "choices": {"A": "(x - 3)2 + (y - 3)2 = 9", "B": "(x - 3)2 + (y - 3)2 = 3", "C": "(x + 3)2 + (y + 3)2 = 9", "D": "(x + 3)2 + (y + 3)2 = 6", "E": "(x + 3)2 + (y + 3)2 = 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. A simple pendulum consists of a small mass suspended from a string that is fixed at its upper end and has negligible mass. The length of time, t seconds, for a complete swing of a simple pendulum can be modeled by the equation , where L is the length, in feet, of the string. If the time required for a complete swing of Pendulum 1 is triple the time required for a complete swing of Pendulum 2, the length of Pendulum 1\u2019s string is how many times the length of Pendulum 2\u2019s string ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "3", "C": "6", "D": "9", "E": "27"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. If  and , then ", "choices": {"A": "2(s + t)", "B": "s + t", "C": "4st", "D": "2st", "E": "st"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Jennifer\u2019s best long jump distance increased by 10% from 1990 to 1991 and by 20% from 1991 to 1992. By what percent did her best long jump distance increase from 1990 to 1992 ?", "choices": {"A": "32%", "B": "30%", "C": "20%", "D": "15%", "E": "2%"}, "correct": "A"}]}